This is hard…
這好難…
You don't have to move if you can't.
不能動就別動也沒關係
The ghosts have gathered.
幽靈聚集起來了
Then in one go, like this…
然後像這樣一口氣…
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I'll take over.
換我來吧
I'm surprised by how good you were.
你很厲害耶，我很驚訝
You'll beat my high score in no time.
你很快就會打破我的高分記錄了吧
And then I remember my own status.
我突然間想起自己的立場
Thirty-two years old.
三十二歲
A virgin.
處女
Well…
那麼…
I have to go this way.
我要走這邊
Oh.
喔
Thank you for today.
今天謝謝你了
Oh, no.
不會
The pleasure is all mine.
我這邊才是
Well then.
再見
Oh, Kagiya!
那個，鍵谷
Would you like to…
你不介意的話…
go for dinner together?
下次要不要一起吃飯？
Huh?
咦？
Yes.
好
Oh, Nana!
喔，菜菜！
It's been ages!
好久不見！
Oh, Mrs. Tsuji.
哇，辻小姐
I heard you got hired again as a part-timer.
我聽說你用打工身分復職了
I did! So, as a way to say hello, here.
對啊，所以來打個招呼，給你
It's homemade.
這是我自己做的
Thank you so much.
謝謝你
Did you gain weight, Nana?
菜菜你是不是胖了？
Oh, I did. I had a baby girl, so…
對啊，生了個女兒，所以…
Is that Mrs. Tsuji?
那位就是辻小姐？
The one who didn't get along with Ms. Misono, right?
和味園超合不來的那一位？
Yeah.
沒錯
She's intense.
真是奔放啊
My son got into the middle school he wanted, so I also…
我兒子考上了 不錯的私立學校，所以…
Sakie Tsuji.
辻咲江
… wanted to get out and about.
…就說想出來透點氣
We got hired at the same time.
我之前的同期同事
Well, my husband is a dentist, so we have money, but…
嗯，我老公是牙醫 所以生活方面完全…
We used to be best friends.
曾經最要好的朋友
I'll go say hi to the others. Good morning!
我要去和其他人打招呼了，早安！
-Good morning. -I'm Tsuji.
-早安 -我是辻
She kept saying we'd work hard together, but she got married and quit right away.
她總是說我們一起努力 結果結婚後卻馬上辭職了
Long time no see, Miyuki.
美由紀，好久不見
I'll be coming twice a week from now on.
今天開始一週兩次要麻煩你關照了
Here, have some.
不嫌棄的話，請吃一點吧
No thanks.
不需要
Now, she has become the woman I hate more than anyone else in the world.
她現在變成全世界我最討厭的女人
Good morning!
早安
Mrs. Tsuji was quite something, huh?
辻小姐真是不得了呢
She was a personality.
很有個性，對吧？
Good job today.
辛苦了
Kodaira, you don't like sweets?
小平你不喜歡甜食嗎？
Oh, no, homemade stuff from strangers is kind of a visceral no-go for me.
啊，不是，我打從心底 不能接受陌生人手工的食物
I see.
這樣啊
Hey, Ms. Misono and Mrs. Tsuji used to be friends, you know.
味園和辻以前是好朋友喔
What?
什麼？
I wonder what went wrong between them.
不知道他們之間發生了什麼事
Human relationships are scary.
人際關係真是可怕，對吧？
A single wrong step can ruin everything.
走錯一步就會全部毀掉
She had friends…
她交的朋友…
I have to make sure not to mess this one up either.
這次一定得確保不會把事情搞砸
…I really can't picture it.
…我真的無法想像
It's right after work, so I shouldn't overdo it either.
畢竟是接在下班後 最好還是收斂一點吧
Which means…
說是這麼說…
It's so grown-up and boring.
太文靜了也很無趣
Friday is fine.
星期五沒問題
"Where is your workplace?"
“你上班的地方是在哪裡呢？”
In Gotanda.
在五反田
"Then let's find somewhere in Gotanda?"
“那就在五反田如何？”
Okay. I'll wait in front of the station.
好，我在車站前面等你
He's so formal.
好正式的感覺
It was a spur of the moment invitation. What if he didn't want to go?
一時衝動就邀了他 不知道他會不會覺得困擾？
What do I do?
怎麼辦？
What if he's not into it?
萬一聊不起來該怎麼辦？
Oh, and the restaurant.
對了，還有餐廳
I don't know what kind of food he likes.
鍵谷不知道喜歡什麼？
GOTANDA ITALIAN
（五反田，義大利餐廳）
Huh, there's this many Italian places?
什麼？那裡有這麼多義大利餐廳喔？
Should I drop by the hairdresser?
我是不是該去一趟美容院？
No, lipstick is more important.
不，更重要的是唇膏
No.
不對
Actually…
更重要的是…
If it's just the two of us, there's a chance of it happening…
兩個人見面，就是說也有那種可能…
What do I do?
怎麼辦？
It's turning into quite a hassle.
感覺事情變得麻煩了
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Nothing.
沒什麼
You and Ms. Misono joined at the same time?
喔，你和味園小姐 是同時期進公司的啊？
We did.
對啊
Miyuki has always worked hard.
美由紀從以前就超級認真
She's still the center of the company. Just like she used to be.
現在也是公司核心的感覺 真是一點都沒變
Who is she calling a center?
什麼核心啊？
You're just mocking me.
只是把我當成傻瓜吧
Retiring upon marriage is so outdated.
再說結婚就辭職也太古板了吧？
She always picked the easy way out.
盡是選擇輕鬆的生活方式
Hey, how about we go camping soon?
我說，下次我們去露營吧？
-Camping? -Yes.
-露營？ -對
We should get out and relax in nature. It's really cool, actually.
偶爾也親近大自然放鬆一下吧？ 真的很棒喔
Have a look at this.
你看看這個
Listen. That's just not happening.
我說啊，那是不可能的
My job doesn't give me as much time off as your little laid-back editor job.
我的工作跟你 悠閒的編輯工作可不一樣
I'm not saying to go right now.
我不是說要馬上去
We'll go when you job calms down a little.
等你工作比較少一點的時候嘛
That's what I just said, I can't just take a long vacation like that.
所以說，我不能請那麼長的假
Nor do I want to.
我也沒打算要請
If I took careless leaves like those young people do,
如果我像年輕人一樣 不管其他人，想請假就請假的話
then a promotion isn't happening either.
就別想要升職了
You know, to begin with,
說到底
the reason I work so hard is because I'm thinking about our future together.
我會這麼拼命工作 還不是為了我們的未來著想
If we were to get married, I'd have to work the hardest.
如果我們要結婚 我不多努力點怎麼行？
You only make half of what I do. If you don't even get--
你的年收入只有我的一半，你根本…
I see.
這樣啊
You're right.
說的也是
I'm sorry.
對不起啊
GOTANDA
（五反田水邊車站）
Why do I feel so uncomfortable?
為什麼感覺這麼沉重？
It's the same feeling as when I'm not in the mood for a drinking party.
參加酒會前也有這種不想去的感覺
I need someone to tell me the name of this phenomenon.
要是有人能告訴我 這種現象的名字就好了
No way, how long has he been standing there?
不會吧？他什麼時候站在那裡的？
Kagiya. I didn't know you were waiting over here.
鍵谷，我不知道你在這邊等
I'm sorry for looking so shabby.
不好意思，我穿這樣子
No, not at all.
不會，不用在意啦
Let's go?
那我們走吧？
Yes.
好
I'm sorry, we're full right now.
不好意思，現在剛好客滿了
Do you have a reservation?
請問有預約嗎？
Oh, I'm afraid the waiting time right now is around one hour…
哎呀，現在可能要等一個小時喔…
Nothing is available.
不行啊
It's Friday after all.
真不愧是星期五
Um…
那個…
Is there a place around here that you like to go to?
這附近有你常去的餐廳嗎？
A place I like to go to?
我常去的嗎？
I can't believe we're having ramen.
沒想到竟然是吃拉麵
I should have reserved a table somewhere.
要是有先預約餐廳就好了
By the way, how old are you?
對了，你幾歲啊？
I'm 29.
我29歲
What? You're so young.
咦？好年輕喔
I'm 32 years old.
我是32歲
Huh? You're older than me?
咦？你年紀比我大嗎？
What?
什麼？
I can never tell a woman's age.
我分不太出來女生的年紀
I've been wondering for a while,
我之前就很想問
but do you wear the mask because of your job?
你是因為工作才戴口罩嗎？
No, I have hay fever.
不是的，我有花粉症
Hay fever?
花粉症？
Yes.
對
Do you have it too?
你呢？
No, not at all.
我是沒有
My brother suffers pretty bad from it, though.
但我哥很嚴重
He keeps his nose like…
他很常像這樣…
He'd crunch this up into his nose like this.
像這樣然後塞進鼻子裡
This feels nice.
感覺真不錯
Much more relaxed than before.
感覺比之前更自然了
The ramen was good, huh?
那間拉麵真好吃呢
We should have ordered some gyoza too.
應該也要點餃子的
Oh, right.
啊，對了
Kagiya, your first name is "Senri", right?
鍵谷的名字是叫“千里”吧？
-Huh? -I saw it on your business card.
-咦？ -我在名片上看到的
You're right. I'm surprised you remembered.
對，沒想到你記得這麼清楚
I thought it was a pretty name.
我覺得是很棒的名字
Was that a weird thing to say?
我說了什麼奇怪的話嗎？
No, it's fine.
不，不會
I'm just feeling a little embarrassed.
只是覺得有點害羞
T-That's so cute.
好…好可愛
I had fun today.
我今天很開心
Thank you.
辛苦了
Um.
那個
-I want to talk more. -If you want to, we…
-我想和你再多聊一下 -你不介意的話…
Ah, no…
啊，不是…
I mean, uh…
我的意思是，那個…
Another time…
下次…
Now is fine too.
現在繼續也沒關係
You could come to my place if you want.
你想來我家也可以
Welcome.
歡迎光臨
Do you drink alcohol?
你喝酒嗎？
A shochu highball then, please.
那…就燒酒，麻煩你了
Okay.
好
There's only alcohol-free here.
這裡只有無酒精飲料
I'll go look at the snacks.
我去看看點心
Okay.
好
Not once since I started living alone have I had a man come over.
開始自己住之後 這是第一次有男生到我家
I went to a women's college,
我是讀女子大學
and never had any romances at work either.
在打工的地方也沒有談戀愛
I had a few crushes now and then,
有時候會遇到覺得不錯的人
but either they were in relationship,
但對方不是有交往對象
or they were married.
就是已經結婚了
So today, Kagiya will be the first man I've ever invited over.
所以今天讓男人到家裡 鍵谷還是頭一個
Are you married or do you have a girlfriend?
你有結婚或是女朋友嗎？
Huh?
什麼？
No. Neither of those.
沒有，沒結婚也沒有女朋友
Thank goodness.
太好了
Me too.
我也是
Cheers.
乾杯
It's so good.
好好喝
Make yourself comfortable, okay?
你可以放輕鬆一點
You can use this.
不介意的話，用這個吧
Thank you.
不好意思
I've never been in a woman's home before.
我第一次到女生家裡
I'm a little nervous.
有點緊張
Oh, really?
是喔，這樣啊
Do you often have men over?
你常邀男生到家裡玩嗎？
Here?
這裡嗎？
This is the first time.
這是第一次
So I'm nervous too.
所以我也很緊張
No one has come over?
一次都沒有？
A boyfriend, maybe.
男朋友之類的？
Never.
沒有
I had a boyfriend in high school, but that's about it.
我只有在高中時交過男朋友而已
I would've never guessed.
看不出來
I'm not sure that's a good thing.
我該感到開心嗎？
Well, I mean, you're…
因為香坂你…
P-Pretty.
很…很漂亮
Oh, no. I'm not really.
不，沒有很漂亮吧
You seem like you can get along with anyone.
感覺你跟誰都能很快成為朋友
That's not true.
才不是那樣
So I was really happy when you said you wanted to talk to me more.
所以你說想多跟我聊聊時，我很高興
Let's have some of these.
來吃這個吧
I want to touch him.
我想碰碰他
Right now,
現在大概…
that's all.
這樣就好
I missed.
錯開了
I'm sorry.
抱歉
I'm terrible at this.
我不是很擅長
Guess they're having a home party too.
隔壁可能也在喝酒吧？
Seems like it.
好像是
They're a little loud.
聲音很讓人在意吧？
Another remarkable achievement.
又一次取得出色成就
Shogi player Shinta Fujimoto
將棋選手藤本新太
got a historic 29th consecutive victory by defeating Motojima Akio
在王將戰首戰擊敗本島昭夫
in the opening match of the Osho Title Tournament League.
取得歷史性的29連勝
Shinta Fujimoto back in January of this year…
藤本新太在今年一月回歸…
Kagiya?
鍵谷？
I'm sorry.
對不起
Wait, Kagiya!
等一下，鍵谷
I'm home.
我回來了
Makoto?
真？
Where did I do wrong?
我是哪裡做錯了呢？
If I knew I'd feel this way, it would have been easier to stay alone forever.
如果會這麼難過 一直單身還比較快樂
It was so fun being together.
在一起時明明很開心的
If you want him back, you need to go to him first.
如果你想要他回來 不先去找他怎麼行？
I'm sorry. I want to see you.
對不起，我想見你
I need to talk to him again.
我想再跟鍵谷說一次話
I don't want it to end yet.
我還不想結束